NAA Additional Records 5796
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
NAA Additional Records
1945-1991
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Academy of Arbitrators (NAA)
5796
7 cubic feet
7 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Committee reports, meeting minutes, financial records and oral histories
5706185
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 20, 2005
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 17, 2019
Scope and Contents
Includes accessions 1985-1991 and oral histories of past presidents.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5246: NAA Records 5775: NAA Records 5985: NAA Additional Files Regarding Proceedings 6004: NAA Additional Records 6004 AV: NAA Audio-Visual Material 6004 OHM: NAA History Committee Oral History Interview Masters 6004 OHT: NAA History Committee Oral History Interview Transcripts 6136: Dennis Nolan Collection of National Academy of Arbitrators History Files 6205: NAA Committee Files 6316: National Academy of Arbitrators Archives Project Records
Arrangement
Series I: Annual Meetings
Series II: Executive Officers
Sub-Series A. Presidents' Files Sub-Series B. Secretaries' Files
Series IV: Committees
Series V: Miscellaneous
Series VI: Oral Histories of Past Presidents
Series VII: Miscellaneous Tapes
Arbitration, Industrial--United States.; Aaron, Benjamin; Abenethy, Bryon; Alexander, Gabriel N., 1910-; Anderson, Arvid A. (Arvid Asa), 1930-; Dash, G. Allen; Dunsford, John E.; Dybeck, Al; Fallon, William J.; Garrett, Sylvester; Jones, Edgar A. (Edgar Allan), 1921-; Kahn, Mark; Kelliher, Peter M.; Killingsworth, Charles, 1917-; Luskin, Bert; McDermott, Clare (Mickey); McKelvey, Jean T. (Jean Trepp), 1908-1998.; Mittenthal, Richard; Robins, Eva; Rock, Eli; Seward, Ralph T. (Ralph Theodore), 1907-; Simkin, William E.; Stark, Arthur; Valtin, Rolf; National Academy of Arbitrators.
5706185
- Series I: Annual Meetings
  - Annual Meeting, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    correspondence, meetings, misc.
  - Annual Meeting, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual Meeting, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Meeting, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    financial records
  - Annual Meetings, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Certification of Attendance
- Series II: Executive Officers
  - Sub-Series A. Presidents' Files
    - Sevard, Ralph T., 1945-1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Organizational Meetings.
    - Killingsworth, Charles C., 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
      Routine.
    - Robins, Eva, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
      Includes: 1981 Annual Meeting; routine.
    - Robins, Eva, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 11-15)
      Includes: Arrangement Committee - 1981 Annual Meeting; routine.
    - Robins, Eva, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Includes: Committee on Development of Arbitrators; routine.
    - Robins, Eva, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Includes: Executive Committee; routine.
    - Robins, Eva, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 18-21)
      Includes: Legal Protection Committee; routine.
    - Robins, Eva, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Includes: Program Committee, routine.
    - Robins, Eva, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Miscellaneous - Sevard discussion; routine.
  - Sub-Series B. Secretaries' Files
    - Bloch, Richard I., 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Includes: Three-year financial review; routine.
    - Annual Reports, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Series III: Board of Governors (Box 1)
  - Committee Reports and Minutes, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Committee Reports and Miscellaneous., 1988 (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
  - Committee Reports and Financial Records., 1988 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Committee Reports, Financial Records, and Miscellaneous., 1988 (Box 1, Folder 30-32)
  - Committee Reports, Financial Records, and Miscellaneous.'., 1989 (Box 1, Folder 33-35)
- Series IV: Committees
  - Academy History, Committee on, 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Academy Structure, Committee on, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Includes: Sevard Report on Structure; reports; routine.
  - Arbitrator Survey Committee, 1962-1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Continuing Cooperation with Appointing Agencies, Committee on, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Includes: Subcommittee report to National Academy Liaison Committee.
  - Disputes Settlement in Public Employment, Committee on, 1969-1977 (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
    Includes: Annual Report 1970-71; Significant Developments During 1973; Significant Developments During 1974; Routine.
  - Ethics Committee, 1953-1967 (Box 2, Folder 10-13)
  - Executive Committee, 1953-1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Future Directions Committee Surveys of Arbitrators. (Box 2)
    loose
  - Future Directions Committee (cont.) Surveys of Arbitrators. (Box 3-4)
  - Legal Protection and Representation, Committee on, 1963-1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Legislation Committee, 1953-1957 (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
    Includes: Reports re Uniform Arbitration Act.
  - Liaison with Judicial Center, Subcommittee on, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Membership Committee, 1947-1981 (Box 5, Folder 5-8)
    Routine
  - Nominating Committee 19693, 1977-1982 (Box 5, Folder 9-11)
    Includes: By-Lavs; Routine.
  - Oral History Project, Committee on, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Overseas Correspondents, Committee on, 1970-1982 (Box 5, Folder 13-16)
    Includes: "Labor Dispute Settlement in the United Kingdom, 1972." by Prof. T.L. Johnston; routine.
  - Professional Insurance, Committee on, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Routine; See also - Professional Responsibility and Grievances, Committee on - Boxes 8-9. RESTRICTED.
  - Public Employment Disp. uteg., Settlement, Committee on, 1977-1979 (Box 5, Folder 18-21)
    Includes: 'Significant Developments in Public Employment Disputes During 1977" by Walter J. Gershenfeld and Joan Weitzman.
  - Publication Committee, 1987-1990 (Box 5, Folder 22-27)
  - Research and Education, Committee on, 1954-1965 (Box 5, Folder 28-31)
    Includes: Study of Costs of Arbitration; "A Statistical Examination of the Radio of Study Days to Hearing Days Charges by Arbitrators.
  - Statutory Regulation of Labor Dispute Arbitration, Committee on, 1956-1966 (Box 5, Folder 32-33)
  - Steering Committee - Code of Professional Responsibility for Arbitrators of Labor-Management Disputes (CODE) - 1st Draft (WES), 1973 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    2/27/73.
  - Steering Committee - CODE 2nd Draft (WES), 1973 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    6/22/73.
  - Steering Committee - CODE 3rd Draft (WES), 1973 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    7/31/73.
  - Steering Committee - CODE 4th Draft (WES), 1973 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    9/30/73.
  - Steering Committee - CODE 5th Draft, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    11/1/73. For General Comment.
  - Steering Committee - CODE, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 39-45)
    11/1/73. Members Comments.
  - Steering Committee - CODE 6th Draft (WES), 1974 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    2/16/74.
  - Steering Committee - CODE 7th Draft (WES), 1974 (Box 5, Folder 47-48)
    3/4/74.
  - Steering Committee - CODE 8th Draft (WES), 1974 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    4/2/7A. For NAA Annual Meeting.
  - Steering Committee - CODE, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1-5)
    Comments on 4/2/74 8th Draft.
  - Steering Committee - HAA Convention, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    4/23/74. Includes discussion re Steering Committee and CODE.
  - Steering Committee - CODE 9th Draft (WES), 1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    6/30/74.
  - Steering Committee - CODE 10th Draft, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    8/24/74.
  - Steering Committee - CODE 11th Draft, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    9/10/74. Final Comments.
  - Steering Committee - CODE 12th Draft (WES), 1974 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    11/12/74. *
  - Steering Committee - CODE, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    10/11/74, 12/74. Board of Governors - comments.
  - Steering Committee - CODE, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    11/30/74. Revised Final.
  - Steering Committee - CODE, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 13-15)
    11/1/73 Draft. 1974. Regional Comments.
  - Steering Committee - CODE, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    11/1/73 Draft. 1974. Other Comments.
  - Steering Committee - CODE: Background Material, 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
  - Steering Committee - CODE: Memos to Steering Committee, 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
  - Steering Committee - CODE: Selected Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1972-1975 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Training of New Arbitrators, Committee on, 1964-1967 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Series V: Miscellaneous
  - Academy Policies 1947-67., 1947-1967 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Aaericall (ITS) 1982. (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - The Chronicle 1977-80., 1977-1980 (Box 6, Folder 25-26)
  - The Corporation Trust Co. 1969-70., 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Dues Waiver 1975-76., 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - ERISA 1978-79., 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Aaron Horvitz Fund 1968-69., 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - NAA Newsletter 1967-68., 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Publications and Speeches 1953-65. Includes: 'Labor Arbitration and Individual Workers* by Louis L. Jaffe., 1953-1965 (Box 6, Folder 32-33)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 6, Folder 33-35)
- Series VI: Oral Histories of Past Presidents
  - Ralph T. Seward, 1947-1949 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - William E. Sinkin, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - G. Allen Dash, Jr., 1959 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Gabriel N. Alexander, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Benjamin Aaron, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Sylvester Garrett, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Peter. Kelliher, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Bert Luskin, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Charles C. Killingsworth, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Jean T. McKelvey, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Eli Rock, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Rolf Valtin, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Arthur Stark, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Richard Hittenthal, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Clare (Mickey) McDermott, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Eva Robins, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Edgar A. Jones, Jr., 1981 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Bryon Abernethy, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Hark Kahn, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - John E. Dunsford, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - William J. Fallon, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Arvid Anderson, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Al Dybeck, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Series VII: Miscellaneous Tapes
  - NAA Tapes of Code Panel - original unedited., 1989 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Vol. 1-2. Chicago, Illinois. Panel discussion with Richard Mittenthal, moderator; Ralph Seward, William Simkin, Eli Rock, and Fred Bullen.
  - NAA unedited tapes of Founding Panel., 1987 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    Vol. 1-3. New Orleans, Louisiana. (Committee on History of Academy)